frontiersin.org 2009-12-27

# Frontiers in Neuroscience - privacypolicy

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By continuing to use this website, you consent to the use of your personal information as described in the Privacy Policy. You and Frontiers agree to comply with Frontiers' Privacy policy as in force from time to time.

## ABOUT US

FRONTIERS take the privacy of all users of the Website very seriously. This Privacy Policy outlines how your personal information will be treated. Our privacy policy will be reviewed and enhanced from time to time and you should check this page to see our most up to date policy. If you would like any further information or have any comments about our Privacy Policy or any other aspect of our website or service, please contact us at : data.controller@frontiersin.org This website, and its access and use by all visitors, are governed by the site terms of use and disclaimers, which you must read and accept as a condition to using this website.

## DATA CONTROLLER

The data controller regarding personal data collected via this website can be contacted on data.controller@frontiersin.org. The data controller is the organisation which controls the purposes for which your personal data is used, and the means used to process and protect that information.

## WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

In order to provide you with our services, we may collect and keep a record of personal information about you from our website. This information may include general information such as your IP address, date/time of the access, details of files or pages consulted, page from which the access took place, top level of the domain name (.com, .ch, etc), internet navigator and operating system used. We may ask you personal information for registration purposes (registration is optional). There will also be explicit feedback forms asking you to provide more personal information such as Name, Location , Profession , Emails etc.. For registered users this may also include specific feedback forms attached to individual articles (and other content type) on the site however the filling in of these specific feedback forms is optional. We may also use cookies (please read below).

## HOW WILL WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?

The data collected during the registration process is kept for identification purposes and is for Frontiers' and its licensees and subcontractors' use only. The data collected may be kept and used by Frontiers and Frontiers' licensees and subcontractors inside and outside Switzerland or your country of residence, for non-commercial and commercial purposes. The data collected will not be communicated to other third parties, except Frontiers' licensees and subcontractors. You may withdraw, reduce or widen your authorisation at any time by notifying your data publicity status in your profile. Frontiers will not sell or disclose your personal information to third parties except as described above. We will usually store your personal information for the period in which you use the website and for a reasonable period after you cease to use it. Please inform us when you cease definitively to use the website We reserve the right to keep information for longer if necessary, for example to investigate breaches of our terms of use. Please select in your profile which of your personal information (if any) you wish to be visible on Frontiers' Website, and whether only to registered users or to all visitors. If you do not selection of privacy level in your profile, your protection will automatically be the highest (i.e Level 5 as specified under).

## EXPERT READERS/AUTHORS/EDITORS/REFEREES

Consent to transfer to licensees and subcontractors: If you do not authorise Frontiers to transfer your personal information to Frontiers' licensees or subcontractors, it will not be possible for you to become an expert reader or fulfil any other Frontiers function. You may still visit the site and read articles but your visits will not be counted towards calculating the impact factor for the articles and authors. If you consent, your personal information can be transferred to Frontiers' licensees and subcontractors and may be used for the purposes of managing Frontiers' websites and journals. Frontiers' licensees and subcontractors may be located outside your country of residence. You may withdraw your authorisation at any time, in witch case any Frontiers function you may hold will automatically terminate and your account will be closed (and your profile will be deleted within a reasonable period).

## INFORMATION AVAILABLE ONLINE (ON FRONTIERS WEBSITE)

In your profile, there are four different selections you can make in terms of privacy regarding your information available online. You can select and modify which level you prefer: 

* Level 1 - Public (all given information visible to all user)   
* Level 2 - Semi-public (basic contact details (first name, last name, affiliation and e-mail address) visible to all user),   
* Level 3 - Internal with all information (all given information visible only to Frontiers registered users)   
* Level 4 - Internal basic information (basic contact details (first name, last name, affiliation and e-mail address) visible only to Frontiers registered users)   
* Level 5 - Private (all given information visible to none) 

## COOKIES

In common with many other website operators, we may use standard technology called 'cookies' on this site. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our cookies enable us to identify you and to store information about the products you select between visits. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent cookies being stored, however if you do turn cookies off this will limit the service that we are able to provide to you. Please ensure that your browser's cookie settings are as you wish. Transfer and use of your information to and in other countries The server on which this website is hosted may be outside the country from which you access this website and may be outside your country of residence. Your information may be transferred across country borders, potentially to countries where data protection laws provide a lower level of protection than in your country of residence. We implement measures, such as contractual confidentiality and non-use obligations, to ensure that your information is kept secure. We take the security of your personal information seriously. We have security procedures in place to protect our visitor database from loss and misuse, and only allow access to it when necessary, and then under strict guidelines as to what use may be made of the personal information contained within it. This website may contain links to other websites. We have no control over and are not responsible for the content of, privacy policies or security of such sites. We recommend that you check the privacy and security policies of each website you visit. Your right to access and manage your personal information You have the right to receive information about the personal data we hold about you and to have your information amended or deleted. A fee may be chargeable for this information, amendment or deletion. To gain access to your personal information stored on this website, or to have it amended or deleted, please contact us via the details provided above.

## ACCURACY OF DATA

You are responsible for maintaining the accuracy of your data and the security of your account and password; and for all activity that occurs on your account, even when content is posted by others under the your account. You undertake: (i) to notify Frontiers immediately of the discovery of any unauthorised use of any password or account or any other known or suspected breach of security; and (ii) to report to Frontiers immediately and use reasonable efforts to stop immediately any unauthorised activity known or suspected. The address for notification is the following: data.controller@frontiersin.org
